<content>
	<numPages>12</numPages>

	<page>INTRODUCTION

This is a Police Officer Manual, it contains the valuable and important information about regulation and the assignments that you have as a Police officer in the SAMPD.

If you follow this manual with guidelines and regulations on how to proceed you will have a career in the best Police department in the United States of America.

If you prove that you can follow this manual and also be a part of 
the development of improving the department you can also be promoted or awarded for your own initiative.

If you only come to your job with a smile and a positive thinking you can also be the best of the best officers in the force.

All your acts reflects upon you fellow officers, if you don’to follow the regulation you will let your colleagues down, the department down and the citizen of San Andreas down.</page>
	
	<page>THE POLICE RADIO

As a police officer for the SAPD, it’s required that you can use your radio. If you go on duty without it you can be suspended or fined for not having the radio on you when you go on duty. And you should also remember that if you are off duty but still gets involved in police work you should maybe tune in to the off duty channels and stay ready to switch to the correct channel when needed.

You have access to several channels on your radio so you should chose the channels well to not confuse any superiors on what you are doing in your current channel.

The radio transmissions are managed by a Central radio transceiver station that is positioned at the police station. This Central station is also called Dispatch.

The dispatch keeps track of all on duty units and organise them and their radio traffic so their jobs can be done as effective as possible. Due to that the radio is one of the Police Officers most powerful equipment it needs to be organised and that job is the Dispatch.</page>

	<page>RADIO CODES

10-1 	Responding (Silent/Loud)
10-2 	Arrived at scene
10-3 	Negative
10-4 	Acknowledgment
10-5 	Repeat
10-6 	Stand-by
10-7 	Report to Location

10-8 	Suspect lost (usually followed by a 10-17)
10-9 	Prisoner secured
10-10 	Activity update (Give your 10-20 and 10-11)
10-11 	Police operation
 		Code 0 - Major incident
 		Code 1 - Pulling over suspect
 		Code 2 - Auto pursuit 
 		Code 3 - Foot pursuit 
 		Code 4 – Special circumstance (Bank robbery, etc.)

10-12 	Police Officer needs assistance
10-13 	Officer down/injured
10-14 	Requesting Black and White
10-15 	Requesting ambulance
10-16 	Requesting towtruck

10-17	Description of Suspect(s)
10-18 	MDC on suspects name
10-19 	Response to MDC

10-20 	Location (should be given as much as possible)
10-30 	Resume normal patrol
10-31 	Returning to PD
10-99 	Assignment complete

Status 1 	Now on duty (Specify with 10-20)
Status 2  	Now off duty
Status 3  	Not available for assignment</page>

	<page>USE OF FORCE

Tier 1 Use of Force - Compliant
Subject Behaviour 
- Compliant and following Officer's direction 

Authorized Use of Force 
- Use Words such as “Please” and” Thank You.” 
- Offer direction and practice patience with subject. 

Tier 2 Use of Force - Contact 
Subject Behaviour 
- Abusive Language; Argumentative. 

Authorized Use of Force 
- Verbal Commands such as HALT, STOP, MOVE, NOW, etc. 

Tier 3 Use of Force - Enhanced Contact 
Subject Behaviour 
- Begins to move around coupled with physical resistance. 
- Subject isn't running, but begins resisting the officer’s orders.

Authorized Use of Force 
- Call other officers on to the scene; Physical presence of more may enact compliance. 
- Continue to use verbal commands to regain compliance. 
- Escalation between 3 and 4 will result in the use of cuffs.</page>

	<page>USE OF FORCE (CONT'D)


Tier 4 Use of Force - Abusive Resistance 
Subject Behavior 
- May attempt to assault officers or others physically. 
- Tries to run and escape.
- Draws a weapon or attempts to pick up object that may be used as a weapon. 

Authorized Use of Force 
- Tazer. 
- Spray. 
- Move subject to vehicle cuffed. 
- You may draw your weapon but not use it.

Tier 4-5 Escalation 
Subject may brandish weapon; Draw weapon at the point subject takes aim at anyone. 

Tier 5 Use of Force - Deadly 
Subject Behaviour 
- Shots Fired 

Authorized Use of Force 
- Deadly Use of Force to counter Subject.</page>
	
	<page>ARRESTING PROCEDURE

State-Mandated Rules on Arrest
------------------------------

Arresting someone is essentially taking away the person's right to freedom. It is a great power and a huge responsibility. The following are the state-mandated rules on arrest. It is our responsibility to ensure the department follows these guidelines in order to keep criminals in jail without legalities setting them free. Failure to follow these guidelines could result in the department or the individual officer getting sued, and your possible termination from the force.

NOTE: Before we go any further, there are times when a situation may call for stepping outside these boundaries. These situations should be few and far between, but it's most important that you, the officer, go home to your family at the end of the day than the criminal. If your actions were founded, the department will stand behind you 100%. 

First, you should stop the suspect's vehicle according to department policies you have learned through training. If the suspect is on foot, disregard this. You should already know what the suspect is wanted for, but if you do not you should quickly run an MDC check on the criminal from the safety of your vehicle.</page>

	<page>ARRESTING (CONT'D)

Felonies: Rape, robbery, murder, assault, stealing police vehicles, hit and run, GTA, kidnapping, rioting, aiding and abetting, fleeing. 

Misdemeanours: Trespass, reckless driving, larceny (less than $250), verbal assault, reckless endangerment, disorderly conduct, illegal racing, gambling, failure to yield for an emergency vehicle. 

Infractions: Traffic violations (failure to stop, driving in wrong lane, nitrous, etc.) 

How you go from here depends on the severity of the crime. Felonies are the highest risk stop there is to make, while infractions typically are a simple ticket or warning. Never get into a routine, though! The one time you let your guard down on that traffic stop is the one time you will wind up in the emergency room or worse!</page>

	<page>FELONIES

Quickly get handcuffs on the suspect to detain him. Most murder suspects will claim self-defence, and it is your job as an officer to also act as an investigator. You should investigate any claim of self-defence by contacting any witnesses, etc. It is important to read the suspect his rights. If he is cooperating. If the suspect at any time starts to dive for a vehicle or run, you should go ahead and finish the arrest by tazing (and if that doesn't help; shooting) the suspect (Also because the suspect has cuffs on, he should not be able to drive, so you have done everything right and he's in the wrong. If he complains he's only hurting himself). If the suspect is still complying you should load them into a patrol car or bandwagon and take them downtown. Do the proper booking and finish the arrest.</page>

	<page>MISDEMEANOURS

Backup is helpful for these stops but not necessarily required. Of course if the suspect attempts to run at any time you should taze the suspect and finish the arrest. It is important to detain the  suspect once you're at the scene for your safety; in other words put cuffs on the suspect and inform them it is for your safety and they are not under arrest at the moment (Again, this keeps us in the clear and allows us to RP the arrest, if they run with handcuffs on and get into a car, report them; They're not RP'ing).

Investigate the situation and determine if the suspect should pay a fine or go to jail. This decision is left to you. If the suspect does manage to get away, this is a felony and should be treated as such.</page>

	<page>INFRACTIONS

Backup is usually never required on a citation as it is a simple ticket. Generally the suspect does not have a warrant at this point. You can freely talk to the suspect through their driver-side window. If at any time they run or pull a firearm the stop immediately becomes a felony and should be treated as such. If the suspect is unable to pay the fine then you should work with the suspect in order to secure the fine. If the suspect does not have the money in his bank, though, it becomes a misdemeanour and the suspect should be arrested. 

And of course, it goes without saying if anyone is shooting at you, you're fully authorized to return fire at the suspect. If another officer is able to sneak behind the suspect and taze him  then by all means go for it, but in no situation should you run straight for a felon with a firearm because you will wind up dead. (Also it is bad RP to run right up to someone with a weapon and /taser. As I said, if another officer can sneak behind to do so, it's fine, but in no situation should you run up to him like Rambo and /tazer).</page>

	<page>MIRANDA WARNING

You have the right to remain silent. Anything you do say may be used against you in a court of law. You also have the right to hire an attorney. If you do not hire one you will be questioned without one present. Knowing and understanding your rights as I have explained them to you, are you willing to answer my questions without an attorney present?</page>

	<page>CREDITS

Created and assembled by:
Sergeant Wesley Adama 89
Ex-Captain Angelo Pappas 83 (Now Hugo Riviera)
Ex-Lieutenant Tony Fox 13 (Fox)
Ex-Lieutenant. Rod Farva XX
Deputy Chief Nathan Daniels 64</page>
</content>